

CHRIS LANE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

C.LANE.DEV@GMAIL.COM

GITHUB.COM/CLLANE

LINKEDIN.COM/IN/CHRISLANEDEV

SKILLS

React jQuery
React/Redux Git
JavaScript OOP
Node.js Sass/SCSS
CSS/HTML TDD/BDD

Agile Workflow Vue.js

PostgresSQL CI

PROFILE

Creative challenges and learning new skills are something I seek in every aspect of my life. After a decade of producing a variety of cuisines in the hospitality industry, I decided to begin a new adventure. Shortly thereafter, I enrolled in Turing School of Software and Design to further my knowledge and found that my skills in collaboration, creative problem solving, and team management could be cultivated in a different way. When I'm not coding, I'm usually hiking, running, playing a board game, or painting.

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE IN WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT WITH REACT, JAVASCRIPT, NODE, HTML, AND CSS

Turing School of Software and Design | May 2019 - November 2019

BIOCHEMISTRY, FINE ARTS

Florida State University | 2008-2012

CODE

COLOR-PICKER | GITHUB.COM/CLLANE/COLOR-PICKER-UI

BACKEND:

Utilizing Node.Js, Knex, and Express to create a functional server which stores user accounts and their created projects in a one to many relationship.

FRONTEND:

Created a user interface with React and Router. A full testing suite was created with Jest and Enzyme.

SPACE-LAUNCH | GITHUB.COM/CLLANE/SPACE-LAUNCH

BACKEND:

This application consumes the Space Launch API.

FRONTEND:

Created a user interface with React, Router, and Redux. A full testing suite was created with Jest and Enzyme.

EXPERIENCE

LINE COOK

HOP ALLEY | OCTOBER 2018 - APR 2019

Managed daily and weekly inventory and food prep. Responsible for menu development over all stations.

PASTA CHEF

ROLF AND DAUGHTERS | AUG 2012 - AUG 2018

Managed other peers on station throughout day. Delegated weekly tasks. Responsible for station inventory, daily preparation of ingredients, and all output during service.